Guide to the Archives of Irish America Newspapers and Periodicals Collection AIA.004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Archives of Irish America Newspapers and Periodicals Collection
Bulk, 1964-2005
1811-2011
AIA.004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
172.75 linear feet in 14 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 172 oversize flat boxes.
The materials in this collection were collected and assembled by the staff of the Archives of Irish America and various donors in an attempt to document the variety of newspapers and other publications produced by and for the Irish American community. It consists of major runs of several prominent Irish American newspapers and periodicals, ranging from general interest weekly newspapers to more narrowly focused, overtly political publications. The collection’s major runs include An Phoblacht / Republican News (1906-present), the official organ of Sinn Féin; Irish Echo (1964-present); Irish People (1972-2004); Irish Voice (1987-2003). The explicitly political publications focus mostly on Irish republicanism and conflict in Northern Ireland.
Archives of Irish America.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Received from Archives of Irish America staff, Consulate General of Ireland, The Irish Bookshop, Cherry Lane Productions, Marion Casey, Linda Dowling Almeida, Mary Lou Powner, Conor McGrady, and Cormac K.H. O’Malley in multiple installments, beginning in 1996. The Nation and Spirit of Freedom included in donations from Sean Prendiville and George Harrison. 19th-century newspapers donated by Sean Prendiville.
Accession number associated with this collection include 1997.007, 1997.018, 1997.059, 2000.025, 2011.005, and 2011.027.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The materials in this collection were collected and assembled by the staff of the Archives of Irish America and various donors in an attempt to document the variety of newspapers and other publications produced by and for the Irish American community.
Scope and Content Note
The Archives of Irish America Newspaper and Periodicals Collections is an intentionally assembled collection of various newspapers and other publications published by and for the Irish American community. It consists of major runs of several prominent Irish American newspapers and periodicals, ranging from general interest weekly newspapers to more narrowly focused, overtly political publications. The explicitly political publications focus mostly on Irish republicanism and conflict in Northern Ireland.
The collection’s major runs include An Phoblacht / Republican News (1906-present), the official organ of Sinn Féin; Irish Echo (1964-present); Irish People (1972-2004); Irish Voice (1987-2003). Also included are regional publications like the Boston Irish News, the Irish American Press from Southern California, and The Tablet from Brooklyn and Queens, New York. Although the majority of the collection dates from the late 20th-century, a few 19th-century papers are present, including the Irish Citizen (1871-1897), Green Banner (1836), and Shamrock (1811).
Of note in the periodicals series are issues of The Nation, published by the Irish American Defense Fund; Spirit of Freedom, an Irish American publication in support of republicanism in Northern Ireland; Irish America, a magazine focusing on the Irish in America and famous Americans of Irish heritage; Ireland of the Welcomes, the official publication of the Ireland Tourist Board; and An Gaodhal, a bi-lingual magazine concerning art, music, and the Irish language.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
George Harrison Papers AIA 009
Irish Republicanism Collection AIA 022
Cormac K.H. O'Malley Papers AIA 019
Patrick Daughton Collection AIA 055
Ernie O'Malley Papers AIA 060
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series: Newspapers and Periodicals. Materials are arranged alphabetically by title, thereunder chronologically.
I. Newspapers, 1836-2011
II. Other Publications, 1881-2008
Irish America.; Irish echo (Boston, Mass.: 1981).; Irish echo.; Irish voice (New York, N.Y.) .; Irish world.; Spirit of Freedom.; The Irish people.; World of Hibernia.; Chicago (Ill.); England.; Irish Americans |v Newspapers.; Irish Americans |v Periodicals.; Irish Americans |z Massachusetts |z Boston |v Newspapers.; Irish Americans |z New York (State) |v Newspapers.; Irish Americans |z New York (State) |z New York |v Periodicals.; Irish Americans |z Pennsylvania |z Philadelphia |v Newspapers.; Journals (periodicals); Magazines (Periodicals); Nation (New York, N.Y.: 1865); Newspapers.; Periodicals.; San Francisco (Calif.)
- I: Newspapers, 1836-2008
  - The Advocate, 1968-1989
    - Nov 2, 1968, Oct 23, 1971, Jan 26, 1974, Mar 19, 1977, Jan 5 1980 - Dec 27, 1980, Jan 30, 1981 - Apr 11, 1981 [Vol. 87, Nos. 4464-4515 (Missing 4467, 4472, 4477, 4503, 4504) Vol. 88, Nos. 4517-4530 (Missing 4516)], Nov 1968-Apr 1981 (Box 1)
    - Apr 18, 1981 – Dec 26, 1981, Jan 2, 1982 – Sep 25, 1982 [Vol. 88, Nos. 4531-4567, Vol. 89, Nos. 4568-4606 (Missing 4591)], 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - Oct 2, 1982 – Dec 25, 1982; Jan 1, 1983 – Dec 31, 1983 [Vol. 89, Nos. 4607-4619, Vol. 89, Nos. 4620-4672, (Missing 4635,4636,4642,4665,4666)], 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    - Jan 7, 1984 – Dec 29, 1984 [Vol. 91, Nos. 4673-4724 (Missing 4694, 4699, 4700, 4702, 4703, 4705, 4708, 4709, 4719)] (Box 4)
    - Jan 5, 1985 – Dec 21, 1985; Jan 4, 1986 – Jun 28, 1986 [Vol. 92, Nos. 4725-4775 (Missing 4741, 4744, 4749, 4752, 4760, 4761, 4765-4767, 4772) Vol. 93, Nos. 4777-4802] (Box 5)
    - Jul 5, 1986 – Dec 27, 1986; Jan 3, 1987 – Sep 26, 1987 [Vol. 93, Nos. 4803-4828 (Missing 4804, 4807, 4809, 4810, 4815, 4822), Vol. 94, Nos. 4829-4867 (Missing 4849)], 1986-1987 (Box 6)
    - Oct 3, 1987 – Dec 26, 1987; Jan 2, 1988 – Dec 24, 1988; Jan 7, 1989 – Apr 22, 1989 [Vol. 94, Nos. 4858-4880, Vol. 95, Nos. 4881-4932 (Missing 4894) Vol. 95/96, Nos. 4934-4949 (Missing 4946)], 1987-1989 (Box 7)
  - American Record: Vol. 1, No. 1; Vol. 11 Mar 17, 1975; May – Jun, 1975; Jul 4, 1975 (Box 144)
  - An Phoblacht / Republican News (Dublin) [For a complete listing of year, volume and number please see Archivist.], 1984-2005
    - Jun 1981, Mar 1984-Jan 1986, Jan 1989-Jun 1994 (with gaps), 1981-1994 (Box 169)
    - Nov 1993, Feb 1994, Mar 1994, 1993-1994 (Box 193)
    - Apr 1994, Jul 1994, Sep 1994 (Box 193)
    - Jul 1994-Dec 1995, 1994-1995 (Box 170)
    - Jan 1996-Jun 1997 (Box 171)
    - Jul 1997 - Dec 1998, Jul 1997-1998 (Box 172)
    - 1999-2000 (with gaps) (Box 173)
    - 2001-2006 (with gaps), 2001-2005 (Box 174)
  - The Boston Irish News, 1986–1990 (Box 146)
  - Catholic New York: Vol. 15, No. 26, Mar 1996 (Box 144)
  - Celtic Connection: Vol. 1, No. 3, Dec 1991, Jan 1992 (Box 144)
  - Celtic Mirror / An Scathan: Vol. 1, Nos. 1, 8, Vol. 3, No. 12, Mar 1995–Feb 1998 (Box 144)
  - Celtic Weekly, Mar 1872–Sep 1873 (Box 147)
  - The Citizen, Mar 1998 (Box 193)
  - Clan-na-Gael Journal (Philadelphia) Aug 5, 1895; Jun 27, 1915, 1895-1915 (Box 158)
  - Fenian News, Vol. 2 and 3, 1930-1931 (Box 158)
  - Florida Irish–American, Nov 1990 (Box 144)
  - Fortnight, Nov 1971–Dec 1971 (Box 144)
  - Gael, Jul 1998 (Box 144)
  - Globe and Emerald (New York) Vol. 2, No. 11, 1825 (Box 149)
  - Green Banner, 1836 (Box 148)
  - The Harvard Crimson, Nov 23, 1963 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 10)
  - Ireland Digest (Dublin), May 1986 (Box 145)
  - Irish American Post, Apr 1992–Apr 2001 (Box 149)
  - Irish American Press (Southern CA), Jul 1989–Nov 1991 (Box 144)
  - Irish American Review (St. Louis, MO), Mar 1987 (Box 144)
  - Irish Arts Center Newsletter, Oct 1992–Oct 1994 (Box 144)
  - Irish Citizen, 1867 October-1871 July (Box 150)
  - Irish Democrat (London) (with gaps), Jan 1984–Jul 1988, Feb 2002-Nov 2005 (Box 145)
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1964-2008
    - Nov 28, 1964; 1966 Easter Rising 50th Anniversary Supplement; Dec 13, 1969; Jul 24, 1971; Apr 22, 1972; Feb 24, 1973, 1964-1973 (Box 8)
    - Mar 3, 1973-Dec 29, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Jan 5, 1974-Dec 28, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Jan 24, 1975-Sep 13, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Sep 20, 1975-Dec 27, 1975; Jan 10-Sep 25, 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 12)
    - Oct 20, 1976-Dec 25, 1976; Jan 1, 1977-Jun 25, 1977, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
    - Jul 2, 1977-Oct 2, 1977; Jan 14, 1978-Dec 30, 1978; Jan 13, 1979-Mar 31, 1979, 1977-1979 (Box 14)
    - Apr 7, 1979-Nov 24, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Jan 5, 1980-Apr 26, 1980 (Box 16)
    - May 3, 1980-Oct 18, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Oct 25, 1980-Dec 27, 1980; Jan 3, 1981-Apr 4, 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 18)
    - Sep 4, 1982-Dec 25, 1982; Jan 1, 1983-Apr 30, 1983, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
    - May 7, 1983-Dec 31, 1983 (Box 20)
    - Jan 7, 1984-Aug 25, 1984 (Box 21)
    - Sep 1, 1984-Dec 29, 1984; Jan 5, 1985-Mar 16, 1985, 1984-1985 (Box 22)
    - Mar 22, 1985-Oct 26, 1985 (Box 23)
    - Nov 2, 1985-Dec 25, 1985; Jan 4, 1986-May 24, 1986, 1985-1986 (Box 24)
    - May 31, 1986-Dec 27, 1986 (Box 25)
    - Jan 3, 1987-Jul 18, 1987 (Box 26)
    - Jul 25, 1987-Dec 26, 1987 (Box 27)
    - Jan 2, 1988-May 5, 1988 (Box 28)
    - May 21, 1988-Sep 17, 1988 (Box 29)
    - Sep 24, 1988-Dec 31, 1988; Jan 7, 1989-Mar 4, 1989, 1988-1989 (Box 30)
    - Mar 11, 1989-Jul 1, 1989 (Box 31)
    - Jul 8, 1989-Dec 30, 1989 (Box 32)
    - Jan 13, 1990-May 29, 1990 (Box 33)
    - May 30, 1990-Oct 16, 1990 (Box 34)
    - Oct 25, 1990-Mar 26, 1991, 1990-1991 (Box 35)
    - Mar 27, 1991-Nov 12, 1991 (Box 36)
    - Nov 13, 1991-Dec 31, 1991; Jan 1, 1992-May 26, 1992, 1991-1992 (Box 37)
    - Jun 2, 1992-Dec 29, 1992 (Box 38)
    - Dec 30, 1992-Jun 8, 1993, 1992-1993 (Box 39)
    - Jun 9, 1993-Oct 26, 1993 (Box 40)
    - Oct 27, 1993-Mar 8, 1994, 1993-1994 (Box 41)
    - Mar 9, 1994-May 15, 1994 (Box 42)
    - May 18, 1994-Sep 27, 1994 (Box 43)
    - Sep 28, 1994-Jan 3, 1995, 1994-1995 (Box 44)
    - Jan 4, 1995-Mar 15, 1995 (Box 45)
    - Mar 22, 1995-Jun 28, 1995 (Box 46)
    - Jul 5, 1995-Sep 20, 1995 (Box 47)
    - Oct 4, 1995-Dec 27, 1995 (Box 48)
    - Jan 3, 1996-May 1, 1996 (Box 49)
    - May 8, 1996-Aug 14, 1996 (Box 50)
    - Aug 21, 1996-Dec 25, 1996 (Box 51)
    - Jan 8, 1997-May 17, 1997 (Box 52)
    - May 28, 1997-Oct 28, 1997 (Box 53)
    - Oct 29, 1997-Dec 24, 1997; Jan 1, 1998-Mar 24, 1998, 1997-1998 (Box 54)
    - Mar 25, 1998-Aug 11, 1998 (Box 55)
    - Aug 12, 1998-Dec 23, 1998 (Box 56)
    - Jan 6, 1998-Jun 1, 1999 (Box 57)
    - Jun 2, 1999-Dec 28, 1999 (Box 58)
    - Dec 29, 1999-May 17, 2000, 1999-2000 (Box 59)
    - May 24, 2000-Oct 4, 2000 (Box 60)
    - Oct 11, 2000-Dec 27, 2000; Jan 3, 2001-Mar 7, 2001, 2000-2001 (Box 61)
    - Mar 14, 2001-Jul 18, 2001 (Box 62)
    - Jul 25, 2001-Dec 26, 2001 (Box 63)
    - Jan 9, 2002-May 15, 2002 (Box 64)
    - May 22, 2002-Oct 9, 2002 (Box 65)
    - Oct 16, 2002-Dec 25, 2002; Jan 8, 2003-Feb 25, 2003, 2002-2003 (Box 66)
    - Feb 26, 2003-Jul 22, 2003 (Box 67)
    - Jul 23, 2003-Dec 9, 2003 (Box 68A)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 68B)
    - 2007 (Box 68C)
    - 2007-2008 (Box 68D)
    - Jul 2008-Nov 2008 (Box 177)
    - Nov 2008-Mar 2009, 2008-2009 (Box 178)
    - Mar 2009-May 2010, 2009-2010 (Box 179)
    - 2011-2014 (Box 186)
    - 2014 (Box 187)
  - Irish Echo Boston Edition: Jan 25, 1986–Dec 27, 1986 (Box 69)
  - Irish Echo Boston Edition: Jan 3, 1987 – Aug 29, 1987; May 7, 1988–May 14, 1988, 1987-1988 (Box 70)
  - Irish Edition (Wyndmoor, PA): 1984-1985; Feb 1986–Jul 1986; Jun 1989–Dec 1989; Jan 1990, May 1990; Jan 1991 [Vol. 4, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 8,9,11), Vol. 5, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 9,10), Vol. 6 Nos. 2-7 (Missing 1,4,6), Vol. 9, Nos. 6-12 (Missing 1-5), Vol. 10, Nos. 1,5, Vol. 11, No. 1], Jan 1984-Jan 2000, 2007-2008 (Box 71)
  - Irish Edition (Wyndmoor, PA): Apr 1993, Jun 1993, Nov 1993, 1994-1996 [Vol. 13, Nos. 4,6,11, Vol. 14, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 2,3,7,9), Vol. 15, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 6,11), Vol. 16, Nos. 1-12, (Missing 2,4,10)] (Box 72)
  - Irish Edition (Wyndmoor, PA): Jan 1997-Jan 2000 [Vol. 17, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 5,11), Vol. 18, Nos. 2-12 (Missing 1,5,9), Marked Vol. 18, Nos. 12, 2-12, Vol. 20, No. 1], 1997-2000 (Box 73)
  - Irish Edition (Wyndmoor, PA): Aug 2003, Jun 2008-Oct 2011 (with gaps), 2003-2011 (Box 182)
  - The Irish Emigrant, 1994–2001, 2006, 2008-2009 (Box 151)
  - The Irish Examiner (New York): Jun 2010-Nov 2010 (Box 175)
  - The Irish Examiner (New York): Nov 2010-May 2011, 2010-2011 (Box 176)
  - Irish Eyes (with gaps), 1995 (Box 145)
  - Irish Herald (San Francisco, CA), Jan 1974–Jul 2000 (Box 152)
  - The Irish Herald, 2001–2003 (Box 153)
  - The Irish Literary Supplement (Selden, NY), 1983-1992, 1994-2004 (Box 154)
  - Irishman (San Francisco, CA), Dec 1984–Mar 1989 (Box 145)
  - Irish People (includes Supplement of Nov. 23, 1867), Jan 1868–May 1876 (Box 155)
  - Irish People (New York), 1972-2004
    - Jul 1972-Dec 1972; Jan 1973-Mar 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 74)
    - Mar 31, 1973-Dec 29, 1973 (Box 75)
    - Jan 5, 1974-Aug 10, 1974 (Box 76)
    - Aug 17, 1974-Dec 28, 1974; Jan 4, 1975-Oct 18, 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 77)
    - Jan 24, 1976-Dec 18, 1976; Jan 1, 1977-Jul 16, 1977, 1976-1977 (Box 78)
    - Jul 23, 1977-Dec 24, 1977; Jan 7, 1978-Apr 8, 1978, 1977-1978 (Box 79)
    - Apr 15, 1978-Dec 23, 1978; Jan 6, 1979-Mar 17, 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 80)
    - Mar 24, 1979-Dec 22, 1979 (Box 81)
    - Jan 12, 1980-Oct 18, 1980 (Box 82)
    - Oct 25, 1980-Dec 20, 1980; Jan 1, 1981-Sep 18, 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 83)
    - Sept 1981-Dec 1981; Jan 1982, 1981-1982 (Box 84)
    - 1981-1985 (Box 192)
    - Feb 1982-Jun 1982 (Box 85)
    - Jul 1982-Dec 1982 (Box 86)
    - Jan 1983-Jun 1983 (Box 87)
    - Jul 1983-Dec, 1983 (Box 88)
    - Jan 1984-Dec 1984 (Box 89)
    - Jan 1985-May 1985 (Box 90)
    - Jun 1985-Dec 1985 (Box 91)
    - 1986 (Box 193)
    - Jan 1986-Mar 1986 (Box 92)
    - Apr 1986-Jul 1986 (Box 93)
    - Aug 1986-Dec 1986 (Box 94)
    - 1986-1991 (Box 188)
    - Feb 1987-Oct 1987 (with gaps); Apr 23, 1988; June 30, 1990; Dec 15, 1990, 1987-1990 (Box 95)
    - 1991 (Box 96)
    - 1992-1995 (Box 190)
    - May-Dec 1992 (Box 97)
    - 1993 (Box 98)
    - Jan 1994-Jun 1994 (Box 99)
    - Jul 1994-Dec 1994 (Box 100)
    - Oct 7, 1995; Oct 5, 1996, 1995-1996 (Box 101)
    - Jan 1997-May 1997 (Box 102)
    - Jun 1997-Dec 1997 (Box 103)
    - Jan 1998-Apr 1998 (Box 104)
    - May 1998-Aug 1998 (Box 105)
    - Sep 1998-Dec 1998 (Box 106)
    - 2000-2004 (Box 191)
    - Jan 2001-Apr 2001 (Box 107)
    - May 2001-Jul 2001 (Box 108)
    - Aug 2001-Dec 2001 (Box 109)
    - Jan 2002-Apr 2002 (Box 110)
    - May 2002-Aug 2002 (Box 111)
    - Sep 2002-Dec 2002 (Box 112)
    - Jan 2003-Jul 12, 2003 (Box 113)
    - Jul 19, 2003-Dec 2003 (Box 114)
    - Feb 2004-Aug 2004 (Box 115)
  - The Irish Press, Nov 23, 1963 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 10)
  - Irish Post: The Voice of the Irish in Britain (London), Jun 1985–Sep 1987 (Box 145)
  - Irish Rebel (Friends of Irish Freedom, Boston), Vol 1, No. 1, Nov 1969 (Box 149)
  - Irish Voice (New York), 1987-2008
    - Dec 5, 1987-Dec 26, 1987: Vol. 1, Nos. 1-4/ Jan 2, 1988-May 21, 1988: Vol. 2, Nos. 1-21, 1987-1988 (Box 116)
    - May 28, 1988-Dec 31, 1988: Vol. 2, Nos. 22-52 (missing 48) (Box 117)
    - Jan 7, 1989-Jun 3, 1989: Vol. 3, Nos. 1-22 (Box 118)
    - Jun 10, 1989-Dec 30, 1989: Vol. 3, Nos. 23-51 (missing 28) (Box 119)
    - Jan 6, 1990-May 19, 1990: Vol. 4, Nos. 1-20 (Box 120)
    - May 26, 1990-Oct 13, 1990: Vol. 4, Nos. 21-41 (Box 121)
    - Oct 20, 1990-Dec 29, 1990: Vol. 4, Nos. 42-51; Jan 5, 1991-Mar 9, 1991: Vol. 5., Nos. 1-10, 1990-1991 (Box 122)
    - Mar 16-May 26, 1991: Vol. 5, Nos. 11-23 (Box 123)
    - Jun 1, 1991-Oct 8, 1991: Vol. 5, Nos. 24-40 (Box 124)
    - Oct 15, 1991-Dec 31, 1991: Vol. 5, Nos. 41-51 (Box 125)
    - Jan 7, 1992-Jul 21, 1992: Vol. 6, Nos. 1-29 (Box 126)
    - Jul 28, 1992 - Dec 22, 1992: Vol 6., Nos. 30-52 (Box 127)
    - Dec 29, 1992-May 25, 1993: Vol. 7, Nos. 1-21, 1992-1993 (Box 128)
    - Jun 1, 1993-Dec 21, 1993: Vol. 7, Nos. 22-51 (missing 52) (Box 129)
    - Dec 23, 1993-Aug 9, 1994: Vol. 8, Nos. 1-32, 1993-1994 (Box 130)
    - Aug 17, 1994-Jan 3, 1995: Vol. 8, Nos. 34-52; Jan 3, 1995-Mar 14, 1995: Vol. 9, Nos. 1-11, 1994-1995 (Box 131)
    - Mar 15, 1995-Jan 2, 1996: Vol. 9, Nos. 12-52 (missing 14, 15, 23, 25, 39), 1995-1996 (Box 132)
    - Dec 20, 1995-Jul 30, 1996: Vol. 10, Nos. 1-31, 1995-1996 (Box 133)
    - Jul 31, 1996-Dec 30, 1996: Vol. 10, Nos. 32-53 (Box 134)
    - Dec 31, 1996-Jul 16, 1997: Vol. 11, Nos. 1-36 (missing 14, 31, 32), 1996-1997 (Box 135)
    - Jul 23, 1997-Dec 30, 1997: Vol. 11, Nos. 38-52 (missing 37, 41, 43, 46) (Box 136)
    - Dec 31, 1997-Jul 22, 1998: Vol. 12, Nos. 1-30, 1997-1998 (Box 137)
    - Jul 29, 1998-Dec 23, 1998: Vol. 12, Nos. 31-52 (missing 50); Jan 6, 1999-Feb 10, 1999: Vol. 13, Nos. 1-7 (missing 2), 1998-1999 (Box 138)
    - Feb 24, 1999-Dec 22, 1999: Vol. 13, Nos. 9-52 (missing 8, 15, 19, 31-34, 36-38, 40, 41, 46, 48) (Box 139)
    - May 10, 2000; Sep 13, 2000; Sep 27, 2000; Oct 4, 2000: Vol. 14, Nos. 20, 38, 40, 41; Jul 11, 2001; Jul 25, 2001; Aug 15, 2001; Aug 22, 2001: Vol. 15, Nos. 29, 30, 32, 34, 35; Feb 13, 2002; Mar 6, 2002; Mar 13, 2002; Mar 27, 2002; Apr 10, 2002; Apr 17, 2002; Apr 21, 2002; May 1, 2002: Vol. 16, Nos. 8, 10-12, 14-19; Sept 10, 2003; Oct 8, 2003; Oct 15, 2003; Nov 19, 2003: Vol. 17, Nos. 37, 41, 42, 47, 2000-2003 (Box 140)
    - Nov 2006-Jul 2007, 2006-2007 (Box 167)
    - Jul 2007- Mar 2008, 2007-2008 (Box 168)
    - Jul 2008-Dec 2008 (Box 180)
    - Dec 2008-Jan 2009, 2008-2009 (Box 181)
  - The Irish World and Industrial Liberator, Jun 1943-Aug 1943 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 10)
  - Irish World: Oct 23, 1971; Feb 2, 1974-Mar 30, 1974, May 17, 1975; Feb 10, 1979; Jan 5, 1980–Dec 20, 1980,; Jan 10, 1981–Mar 28, 1981 [Vol. 102, No. 5288, Vol. 104, Nos. 5407 – 5409, 5413-5415, Vol. 105, No. 5494, Vol. 109, No. 5689, Vol. 110, Nos. 5732-5782 (Missing 5741,5754), Vol. 111, Nos. 5785-5796 (Missing 5794)], 1971-1981 (Box 141)
  - Irish World: Apr 4, 1981–Dec 26, 1981; Jan 2, 1982–Dec 25, 1982 [Vol. 111, Nos. 5797-5837 (Missing 5801-5803,5814,5823), Vol. 112, Nos. 5838-5889 (Missing 5879)], 1981-1982 (Box 142)
  - Irish World: Jan 1, 1983–Dec 24, 1983; Jan 7, 1984–Nov 17, 1984 [Vol. 113, Nos. 5890-5941 (Missing 5908,5937), Vol. 114, Nos. 5932-5985 (Missing 5962,5968,5973-5975,5983)], 1983-1984 (Box 143)
  - National Hibernian Digest, Jan 1974–May 1984 (Box 156)
  - National Hibernian Digest (with gaps), 1989, 2001-2011 (Box 184)
  - New York Times, 1862, 1995 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 10)
  - The Phoenix (New York), 1859-1861 (Box 185, Reel R-7943)
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    Digital access to The Phoenix is available through the University of Missouri Digital Library: http://dl.mospace.umsystem.edu/mu/islandora/object/mu%3A1249
    Custodial History note
    The physical copy of The Phoenix in Box 185 was donated to the archives by Sean Prendiville and separated from his personal papers (AIA 005).
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Due to the fragility of the physical copy of this publication, researchers must use either the microfilm or online version before requesting the original.
  - Plain Dealer "PD Action Tab", Mar 1973 (Box 145)
  - San Francisco Gael, Feb 1993–Mar 1994 (Box 145)
  - Saoirse (Irish Freedom)(Dublin) (with gaps), May-Oct 1972, May 1987–Oct 1998, Jan 2005-Jun 2011 (Box 183)
  - Shamrock News, Mar 1976 (Box 145)
  - Shamrock Newspaper (NY), 1811 (Box 158)
  - South Boston On-Line Print Edition, Jul 2001 (Box 145)
  - Sovereign Nation (Dublin), Oct 1998, Aug 2001 (Box 145)
  - Tablet (Queens and Brooklyn, NY), Mar 1996 (Box 145)
  - Threshold, Sep 1981 (Box 145)
  - Tom Mannion Travel Supplement, Feb 1985 (Box 145)
  - TWU Express, Dec 1963 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 10)
  - United Irishman (Dublin), 1955–1961 (Box 149)
  - United Irishman (Dublin), Aug 1971-May 1972 (Box 149)
- II: Periodicals, 1881-2008
  - Ais Eiri: The Magazine of Irish-America, 1979-1981 (Box 160, Folder 1A)
  - American Committee for Irish Studies, 1963-1964, 1966-1968, 1970 (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - American Committee for Irish Studies, 1971-1976 (Box 160, Folder 2)
  - American Committee for Irish Studies, 1977-1979 (Box 160, Folder 3)
  - American Gael, 1992-1999 (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - American Irish Newsletter American Irish Political Education Committee, 1993-1997 (Box 160, Folder 5)
  - American Irish Newsletter American Irish Political Education Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 160, Folder 5A)
  - American Irish Newsletter American Irish Political Education Committee, Feb 2000-Jul 2000 (Box 160, Folder 5B)
  - American Journal of Gaelic Culture (Chicago), 1996-1997 (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - An Claidheamh Soulis, Inc. - Newsletter - Litir Nuacht, 1971-1977 (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - Sword of Light,The Irish American Review, 1974 (Box 160, Folder 7)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc.- Ais-Eiri The Magazine of Irish America, Win 1979-Spr 1982 (Box 160, Folder 8)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1982-1983 (Box 160, Folder 9)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1984-1985 (Box 160, Folder 10)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1986 (Box 160, Folder 11)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1987 (Box 160, Folder 12)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1990-1992 (Box 160, Folder 13)
  - An Doras, 1996-1998 (Box 160, Folder 14)
  - An Gaodhal, 1881, 1886-1889 (Box 166, Folder 10)
  - An Gaodhal, 1890 (Box 166, Folder 11)
  - An Gaodhal, 1891, 1893-1894 (Box 166, Folder 12)
  - An Gaodhal, 1896 (Box 166, Folder 13)
  - An Gaodhal, 1897-1899 (Box 166, Folder 14)
  - An Gaodhal, 1900-1902 (Box 166, Folder 15)
  - Bard, The, 1996-1999 (Box 160, Folder 15)
  - Beyond Ben Bulben (Australia), 1996-1997 (Box 160, Folder 16)
  - Bonded Shores, 1994-2000 (Box 160, Folder 17)
  - The Bridge: An Droichead, 1986-1987 (Box 160, Folder 18)
  - Callahan's Irish Quarterly, 1977-1981 (Box 160, Folder 19)
  - Callahan's Irish Quarterly, 1982-2008 (Box 160, Folder 20)
  - Carn: A Link Between Celtic Nations, 1974-1978 (Box 160, Folder 21)
  - Celtic News Service, 1975-1977, 1992-1996 (Box 160, Folder 22)
  - Celtic Renewal, 1995 (Box 160, Folder 23)
  - Cois na Farraige, 1984 (Box 160, Folder 24)
  - Desert Shamrock, 1994 (Box 160, Folder 25)
  - Ducas, 1971-1981 with gaps (Box 161, Folder 26)
  - Ducas, 1985-2002 (Box 161, Folder 27)
  - Eire Ireland, 1963-1968 (Box 161, Folder 1)
  - Eire Ireland, 1969-1973 (Box 161, Folder 2)
  - Everyman, 1994-1995 (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - Gaelic Journal, 1900 (Box 161, Folder 4)
  - Gander, 1993-1997 (Box 161, Folder 5)
  - Gander, 1998-1999 (Box 161, Folder 6)
  - Gander, 1999-2001, 2002, 2004 (Box 161, Folder 7)
  - Harp: "Voice of the Irish Impression", Jun 1988 (Box 161, Folder 8)
  - Here's Me Bus!, 1995-1996 (Box 161, Folder 9)
  - Hibernian Life (Minneapolis, MN): vol. ii, no. 3, Jul-Sep 1989 (Box 166, Folder 16)
  - Holy Cross Quarterl y: The Irish Issue, Vol. 6, Nos. 1-4. College of the Holy Cross, Worcester, MA., 1974 (Box 161, Folder 9A)
  - Hornpipe: Irish Dance, Music and Culture in North America, 1999 (Box 161, Folder 10)
  - Inside Ireland, 1984, 1999 (Box 161, Folder 11)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, Mar 1966-Mar 1978 (Box 161, Folder 12)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1984 (Box 161, Folder 13)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1985 (Box 161, Folder 14)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1986 (Box 161, Folder 15)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1987 (Box 161, Folder 16)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1988 (Box 161, Folder 17)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1989 (Box 161, Folder 18)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1990 (Box 161, Folder 19)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1991 (Box 162, Folder 20)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1992 (Box 162, Folder 21)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1993 (Box 162, Folder 22)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1994 (Box 162, Folder 23)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1995 (Box 162, Folder 1)